Inventory of the James Barron Hope Papers (I) 1790-1965
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
James Barron Hope Papers (I), 1790-1965.
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Mss. 65 H77
933 items.
Letters, manuscript poems, editorials, stories, a play, and sketches of James Barron Hope and correspondence of Hope with his mother, Mrs. Jane A. Hope, with his daughters, Mrs. Janey B. Marr and Nanny Hope, and with Caroline Campbell, his cousin, Samuel Barron, and others. 1835-1907.
Jubal Anderson Early,; Benjamin Stoddert Ewell,; Hugh Blair Grigsby,; James Barron Hope,; Fitzhugh Lee,; William Henry Fitzhugh Lee,; Thomas Nelson Page,; John Tyler,; Robert C. (Robert Charles) Winthrop.
Administrative Information
Restrictions on Access
Collection is open to all researchers.
Acquisition Information
Gift: 933 items, 1945-1961.
Biographical/Historical Information
James Barron Hope was born 23 March 1829 in Norfolk, Virginia. He was the grandson of James Barron and son of Wilton and Jane A. (Barron) Hope. James Barron Hope graduated from the College of William and Mary. He practiced law and was commonwealth's attorney for Norfolk. He married Anne Beverley Whiting. The couple had two daughters, Jane A. Barron (Janey Barron Marr) and Nanny Hope. Hope is known primarily for his poetry, serving as the official poet of the 250th anniversary of the Jamestown settlement. He published several volumes of writings and also edited newspapers. Hope died in 1887.
Scope and Content Information
Papers, chiefly 1847-1887, of James Barron Hope. Correspondence includes letters to his mother Jane A. Barron Hope while on a naval cruise to the Caribbean and letters to his wife, Annie Beverley Whiting Hope written during the Civil War. There are letters between Jane A. Barron Hope and her friend, Caroline Matilda Campbell. Prominent correspondents in the collection include Jubal A. Early, Benjamin S. Ewell, Hugh Blair Grigsby, Fitzhugh Lee, W. H. F. Lee, Thomas Nelson Page, John Tyler and Robert Charles Winthrop.
The collection also includes editorials, atories, a play, manuscript poems of Hope including his address at the Yorktown Centennial, as well as articles and letters concerning his death and his involvement in dueling.
Arrangement
Organization
This collection is organized into 9 series; Series 1 contains the papers of James Barron Hope; Series 2 contains certificates and scrapbooks; Series 3 contains Literary and artistic works of James Barron Hope; Series 4 contains newspaper and periodical articles written by or concerning James Barron Hope; Series 5 contains compositions and other literary materials; Series 6 contains items collected by Ann W. Marr, the granddaughter of James Barron Hope; Series 7 contains items collected by Janey Hope Marr, the daughter of James Barron Hope; Series 8 contains miscellaneous items; and Series 9 contains various issues of newspapers.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged chronologically by date within each series. The series are arranged according the various dates which the materials were acquisitioned or added to the collection.
Additional Related and Bibliographic Material
Bibliography
The following articles can be found in the magazine the Virginia Cavalcade, Swem Library Stacks, College of William and Mary. Call Number: F221. V8
Simms, Lyman Moody. James Barron Hope, Virginia's Laureate. In Virginia Cavalcade. Vol. 19, No. 3 (1970), pages 22-29
Wermuth, Paul Charles. An Ode to Reconciliation. In Virginia Cavalcade. Vol. 7, No. 2 (1957), pages 14- 17.
Related Material
There are three collections within the Manuscripts and Rare Books Department, Swem Library, College of William and Mary that relate to this Collection. They include the James Barron Hope Paper (II), the Samuel Barron Papers and the James Barron Papers.
The James Barron Hope Papers (II), Manuscripts and Rare Books Department, Swem Library, College of William and Mary; including correspondence and literary works, chiefly 1861-1874, of James Barron Hope (1829-1887), soldier, author (poet, orator, and novelist), and newspaper editor, of Norfolk and Williamsburg, Virginia.
James Barron Hope Papers (II), 829-1887.195 items.Collection number: Mss. 93 H77
The Samuel Barron Papers, Manuscripts and Rare Books Department, Swem Library, College of William and Mary; include papers and correspondence of three generations of Samuel Barrons, all of whom were involved in naval affairs.
Samuel Barron Papers, 1793-1942.538 items.Collection number: Mss. 65 B29
The James Barron Papers, Manuscripts and Rare Books Department, Swem Library, College of William and Mary; include correspondence and papers of Commodore James Barron relating to his career in the United States Navy, and especially relating to the Chesapeake-Leopard Affair in 1807 and to his duel with Stephen Decatur.
James Barron Papers, 1776-1899.2,759 items.Collection number: Mss. 65 B27
Index Terms
Persons:
Early, Jubal Anderson, 1816-1894.; Ewell, Benjamin Stoddert, 1810-1894.; Grigsby, Hugh Blair, 1806-1881.; Lee, Fitzhugh, 1835-1905.; Lee, William Henry Fitzhugh, 1837-1891.; Page, Thomas Nelson, 1853- 1922.; Tyler, John, 1790-1862.; Winthrop, Robert C. (Robert Charles), 1809-1894.
Subjects:
American poetry--19th century.; Dueling-- Virginia.
Geographical Names:
Yorktown (Va.)--History--Siege, 1781--Centennial celebrations, etc.
Occupations:
Poets, American--19th century-- Correspondence.
Components List
  Series 1: Papers of James Barron Hope,
- Papers of James Barron Hope, 1835-1963, n.d. (Box 1-2)
  - Box 1, 1835-1963, n.d. (Box-folder 1:1-125)
    Box 1 consists the letters of James Barron Hope to his mother, Mrs. Jane A. Hope, while on a U.S. Cruiser in the Caribbean and of his mother to her friend, Miss Caroline H. Campbell, 1852-1858, as well as Hope's letters to Annie B. Whiting before his marriage to her and their correspondence during the Civil War, 1855-1865. An invitation from the Virginia General Assembly requesting that Hope read his poem there, 1858, and a Master of Arts degree from the College of William and Mary, 1866, are also included.
    - Notes written by Anne W. Marr, Norfolk, concerning the letters of James Barron Hope, March 1963., 2 pages. TDr. (Box-folder 1:1)
    - Genealogical Chart of the James Barron Hope Papers, prepared by Sydney A. Temple, Jr., February 1965. (Box-folder 1:2)
    - A brief biography of James Barron Hope, unsigned, n.d. (Box-folder 1:3)
      Apparently intended to accompany the poem Leoni Di Monota.
    - Notes regarding letters of Mrs. Jane A. Hope, n.d. (Box-folder 1:4)
    - Notes, endorsed: "Notes made by Janey Hope-Marr in the later years of her life," n.d. (Box-folder 1:5)
    - "James Barron Hope by Janey Barron Hope Marr," n.d., 5 pages. ADr. C. (Box-folder 1:6)
      Cover endorsement: "Copy of Sketch of Jas. Barron Hope sent to Judge French."
    - J[ane Barron] Hope, Norfolk, to her father [Commodore James Barron], 3 January 1835. (Box-folder 1:7)
      Letter sent on his birthday Letter concerns new home. Endorsement: "From my Father's mother, who was Miss Jane Barron: Buried in Warrenton, North Carolina" [by Janey Hope Marr].
    - H. A. Steinbeck, Surgn. USA, Fort Monroe, Virginia, to Mr. James Barron Hope, Hampton, Virginia, 29 August 1849. (Box-folder 1:8)
      Congratulations on recovery of a wound and a bill for services. Endorsement: "Hope-Jones duel." (see brief biographical note.)
    - Charles, Count de Miollis, "Ashwood Hall," near Columbia, Tennessee to [?], 7 August 1850. (Box-folder 1:9)
      Letter concerns events in his life in last seven years, including service as teacher in the family of Bishop Otey. Endorsement: "Who taught James Barron Hope french."
    - James [Barron Hope], Ship "Penn," to "Mother" [Mrs. Jane Hope], 13 March 1851. (Box-folder 1:10)
      Letter concerns visit with his father and service on the ship.
    - Mrs. Jane A. Hope, Hampton, to Miss Campbell, [Washington City]; 21 October 1851. (Box-folder 1:11)
      Sorrow for "the Absent One."
    - James [Barron Hope], U.S. Ship "Cyane," Home Squadron, off Pensacola Navy Yard, to "Mother," 11 December 1851. (Box-folder 1:12)
    - James [Barron Hope], U.S. Ship "Cyane," Chagries, Centl. Amer., to "Mother," 15 February 1852., 20 pages. ads. (Box-folder 1:13)
      Detailed description of the places he has visited in the Caribbean Sea.
    - James [Barron Hope], U.S.S. "Cyane," St. lago de Cuba, to his mother, Mrs. Jane A. Hope, Hampton, Virginia, 25 March 1852. (Box-folder 1:14)
      Description of Cuba; his 23rd birthday; expressions of great affection for his mother; enclosing a poem (now lost.)
    - [James Barron Hope], U.S.S. "Cyane," at Sea, to his mother Mrs. Jane A. Hope, Hampton, Virginia, 14 April 1852., 12 pages. ads. C. (Box-folder 1:15)
      Description of Trinidad, St. Domingo and Caribbean cruise.
    - J[ane] A. Hope, Hampton, to Miss Caroline H. Campbell, Washington City, D.C., 8 May 1852. (Box-folder 1:16)
      Letter concerns her son [James Barron Hope] at Pensacola; of her lamented father (Comm. James Barron) and the circumstances surrounding his Court Martial; of her mother.
    - James [Barron Hope], U.S. Ship "Cyane," Home Squadron, off Pensacola Navy Yard, to Mrs. Jane A. Hope, Hampton, Virginia, 14 May 1852. (Box-folder 1:17)
      Letter concerns his affection for his mother; of the Roman Catholic faith.
    - James Barron Hope, U.S. Ship "Cyane," to Mrs. Jane A. Hope, Hampton, Virginia, 6 June 1852. (Box-folder 1:18)
      Letter concerns his impending departure for home.
    - J[ane] A. Hope, Hampton, to Caroline [Campbell],17 July 1852. (Box-folder 1:19)
      James [Barron Hope] has returned to Norfolk on the ship "Cyane"; he graduated in Law at William and Mary at the age of eighteen.
    - Jane A. Hope, Hampton, to Miss Caroline H. Campbell, Washington City, D.C., 16 September 1852. (Box-folder 1:20)
      Letter concerns her discontent with Capt. Pain's navigation of the Ship "Cyane"; James [Barron Hope] is planning to enter the practice of law.
    - Jane A. H[ope], Hampton, to Caroline H. Campbell, Baltimore, Maryland, 2 February 1853. (Box-folder 1:21)
      James [Barron Hope], while ill, has employed himself in writing; pertaining to her visit Virginia; wife of Capt. Pendergast.
    - Jane A. Hope, Hampton, to Caroline [Campbell],19 April 1853. (Box-folder 1:22)
      James [Barron Hope] is away in York.
    - Jane A. Hope, Hampton, to Caroline [Campbell],20 October 1853. (Box-folder 1:23)
      "James often employs himself in his writing."
    - J[ane] A. Hope and J[ames] B[arron] Hope, Hampton, to Caroline [Campbell],30 December 1853. (Box-folder 1:24)
      Letter concerns "the Massard Mss." which were sent with books and paintings as a Christmas gift.
    - J[ames] Barron Hope to Miss Annie, 23 March 1855. (Box-folder 1:25)
      Enclosed poem (now lost) on his 26th birthday.
    - James [Barron Hope],[Richmond], to "Mother" (Date and place in an endorsement), [27 October 1855]. (Box-folder 1:26)
      Letter concerns his activities after his arrival there.
    - Carry [Caroline H. Campbell], Baltimore, to "Brother Jeemes" [James Barron Hope], 26 June 1856. (Box-folder 1:27)
      Hope's Mss. have been sent to the Publisher, Mr. Lucas, after being rearranged and edited by Caroline; mentions many of the poems by name, including those addressed to Miss Annie.
    - "Hampton, Monday", 1 September 1856. (Box-folder 1:28)
      Endorsement: "Picture of Mrs. Jane Hope, her son, and Miss Campbell, it is supposed."
    - Annie [B. Whiting], Shell Banks, [Elizabeth City County, Virginia], to Miss Carrie, 2 October 1856. (Box-folder 1:29)
    - James [Barron Hope] to Miss Caroline H. Campbell, Baltimore, 4 January 1857. (Box-folder 1:30)
      Letter concerns paintings.
    - James [Barron Hope] to "Sister Carry" [Caroline H. Campbell], 9 January 1857. (Box-folder 1:31)
      Letter concerns Annie, and his book which appears to be well received in Norfolk.
    - "Jeemes" [James Barron Hope] to "Sister Carry" [Caroline H. Campbell], 14 January 1857. (Box-folder 1:32)
      Letter discusses her care for Annie and her review of his works.
    - James [Barron Hope] to Carry [Caroline H. Campbell], 31 January 1857. (Box-folder 1:33)
      Letter concerns his departure for Richmond.
    - James [Barron Hope] to Carry [Caroline H. Campbell], 27 February 1857. (Box-folder 1:34)
      Letter discusses his mother's health; and his employment at the County Court.
    - J[ane] A. Hope, Hampton, to Caroline [Campbell],6 March 1857. (Box-folder 1:35)
      Letter concerns her sisters in Washington.
    - [Jane A. Hope], Hampton, to Caroline [Campbell],16 March 1857. (Box-folder 1:36)
      Letter concerns Caroline's expected marriage.
    - [Annie Whiting], Hampton, to Carrie [Campbell],26 March 1857. (Box-folder 1:37)
      Letter discusses her trip by steamer, being met at Old Point by Mr. [James Barron] Hope.
    - J[ane] A. H[ope], Hampton, to Caroline [Campbell],1 April 1857. (Box-folder 1:38)
      Letter discusses the visit of the "Merrimac" and Capt. Pendergast's description of a trip to England and the Continent.
    - James [Barron Hope], Hampton, Virginia, to "Sister Carry" [Caroline H. Campbell], 2 April 1857. (Box-folder 1:39)
      Letter concerns meeting with Annie; enclosure of a poem for review.
    - P. R. Fendall, Washington, to John R. Thompson, Richmond, Virginia, 3 April 1857. (Box-folder 1:40)
      Letter concerns the celebration of the settlement of Jamestown, at which Mr. [James Barron] Hope is expected to read a poem.
    - J[ane] A. Hope, Hampton, to Caroline H. Campbell, 4 May 1857. (Box-folder 1:41)
      Letter concerns family matters.
    - James [Barron Hope] to Carry [Caroline H. Campbell], [4 June l857]. (Box-folder 1:42)
      Letter concerns her review of "Leoni"; his marriage on the 10th at "Elmwood," despite the opposition of Mr. Whiting.
    - J. P. R. James, British Consulate, Richmond, Virginia, to James Barron Hope, Hampton, Elizabeth City County, Virginia, 2 July 1857. (Box-folder 1:43)
      Acknowledges receipt of a volume of Hope's poems.
    - Jane A. Hope, Hampton, to Caroline M. Campbell, Baltimore, Maryland, 1 August 1857. (Box-folder 1:44)
      Letter discusses the marriage of James Barron Hope to Annie Whiting.
    - James [Barron Hope] to "Sister Carry" [Caroline H. Campbell], [September 1857]. (Box-folder 1:45)
      Three months after his marriage. Letter concerns a play that he has written.
    - [Mrs.] J[ane] A. Hope, Hampton, to Caroline [Campbell],16 October 1857. (Box-folder 1:46)
      Letter discusses family affairs.
    - J[ane] A. Hope, Hampton, to Caroline H. Campbell, 3 June 1858. (Box-folder 1:47)
      Letter concerns her relatives on ships, from European waters to China.
    - [Mrs.] Annie [Hope], Hampton, to Carrie [Campbell],22 June 1858. (Box-folder 1:48)
      Letter concerns her work with her husband, James Barron Hope, in his writing.
    - J[ane] A. Hope to Caroline [Campbell],n.d. (Box-folder 1:49)
      Condolences on a death in the family.
    - Members of the General Assembly, Richmond, to James Barron Hope, 23 February 1858. (Box-folder 1:50)
      Request signed by 84 members of the General Assembly and 5 Richmond citizens that he recite again as they failed to hear delivered.
    - [Mrs.] Annie [Hope] to Carrie [Campbell],31 January 1859. (Box-folder 1:51)
      Letter discusses the expectation of their first child, and talks of her reading and other activities as a young housewife.
    - James Barron Hope to Sister Carry [Caroline H. Campbell], 4 May 1859. (Box-folder 1:52)
      Letter concerns her letter to his mother.
    - Jane A. Hope, Hampton, to Caroline [Campbell],[31 December 1859]. (Box-folder 1:53)
      Greetings and good wishes for the New Year.
    - James [Barron Hope], Weldon, North Carolina, to his wife Annie and his mother, soon after leaving home, 4 June 1861. (Box-folder 1:54)
    - James [Barron Hope], Richmond, to his wife Annie Barron Hope, Warrenton, [North Carolina], and his children Annie and Jane, 6 June 1861. (Box-folder 1:55)
      Quartered in the Poor House in Richmond.
    - James [Barron Hope] to his mother, 7 June 1861. (Box-folder 1:56)
      Everyone in good spirits in the Capital [Richmond]; 20,000 men in the army in Virginia and is daily increasing; 8,000 in the York region.
    - James [Barron Hope] to his mother, 11 June 1861. (Box-folder 1:57)
      Letter concerns the battle at Bethel where "the Hamptonians behaved with distinguished gallantry."
    - [James Barron Hope], Cirtis Peek [?], Jas. Run, to his wife, 12 June 1861. (Box-folder 1:58)
      A large force has been sent to York; he is engaged in getting men for Barron's battery; going to Williamsburg.
    - James [Barron Hope], Richmond, to his mother, wife, and babies, [June 1861]. (Box-folder 1:59)
      Letter concerns recruiting in Williamsburg.
    - James [Barron Hope],"Goshen," Glo'ster, Virginia, to his wife Annie, 13 June 1861. (Box-folder 1:60)
      Letter discusses the Yankee's loss of 525 at Bethel to Confederate. 1 killed and 7 wounded; Magruder commanded, Col. Hill praised for "cool valor"; flight of a Zouave Regiment.
    - Mary A. Taylor, Williamsburg, to Mrs. Hope, 18 June 1861. (Box-folder 1:61)
      Letter concerns Hope's Hotel and the quiet situation in Williamsburg.
    - James [Barron Hope], Half Way House, York County, to his wife, 18 June 1861. (Box-folder 1:62)
      On way to Williamsburg; faith and moral strength.
    - James [Barron Hope] to Mrs. James Barron Hope, care of J. Wilcox, Warrenton, North Carolina, [20 June 1861]. (Box-folder 1:63)
      Force retired from Bethel to the defenses of Yorktown; alarms in Williamsburg.
    - Mrs. Jane A. Hope, Warrenton, [North Carolina], to her son James [Barron Hope], and his wife Annie to her husband [James Barron Hope], 20 June 1861. (Box-folder 1:64)
      Letter discusses life in their retreat, including "a great annoyance...Julia is not in a condition to nurse the children much longer...."
    - James Barron Hope, Williamsburg, to his wife Annie, 24 June 1861. (Box-folder 1:65)
      Enclosed letters to Jane, Nan and to Sam [Barron] on same sheet.
    - Maria [?] at Yancy's to [Henry] Clay [Whiting],10 July 1861. (Box-folder 1:66)
      Letter concerns the Yankees in town; reference to letter sent to Annie Hope. Endorsement on cover, address to Mrs. James Barron Hope, Warrenton, North Carolina.
    - James [Barron Hope], Commandant's Office, Navy Yard, to his wife, 16 July 1861. (Box-folder 1:67)
      Letter concerns Capt. Barron and Mrs. Barron.
    - H. Clay Whiting, Williamsburg, Virginia, to [James Barron] Hope,18 July 1861. (Box-folder 1:68)
      Application for paymaster's position, until then he is in the Wythe rifles; parents behind the Federal lines who have been forced to take oath of loyalty.
    - James [Barron Hope], Commandant's Office, Navy Yard, Gosport, to his wife Annie, 20 July 1861. (Box-folder 1:69)
      Letter concerns the confidence there, after victory at Manassas.
    - "Papa" James [Barron Hope] to his mother, [July 1861]. (Box-folder 1:70)
      Mention of Comm. Samuel Barron and Capt. Samuel Barron.
    - "Papa James" [James Barron Hope] to his wife, [July 1861]. (Box-folder 1:71)
      Mentions General Johnson, "the Manassas man"; Generals Lee and Magruder; his own children Jamie and Anne.
    - James [Barron Hope] to Mrs. James Barron Hope, at Mr. Wilcox's, Warrenton, North Carolina, and to his mother and children, 20 July 1861. (Box-folder 1:72)
      Letter concerns elegance of the life at his grandmother's place [Mrs. James Barron]; his activity in writing for the Confederate cause.
    - [James Barron Hope] to his wife Annie, 24 July 1861. (Box-folder 1:73)
      Letter concerns attacks aimed at Richmond which were defeated at Manassas; the war in Missouri; Mr. Lincoln's troubles; confidence in the ultimate result, "the Nation born at Sumter and baptised with blood at Manassas will be hailed by the great powers of Europe as a member of the family of Empires."
    - James [Barron Hope], Commandant's Office, Navy Yard, Gosport, to his mother, 25 July 1861. (Box-folder 1:74)
      Letter discusses "God-sent overthrow" of Scott at Manassas; "another battle has taken place in our peninsula."
    - James [Barron Hope] to his wife Mrs. James Barron Hope, Warrenton, North Carolina, 13 August 1861. (Box-folder 1:75)
      "There's a box of champagne for you at the Express Office...."
    - James [Barron Hope] to his wife, 21 August 1861. (Box-folder 1:76)
      Letter concerns his poem in the newspaper, family matters; encloses newspaper clipping of Land as a medicine.
    - Louisa Whiting, Audley, Westmoreland, to James Barron Hope, Navy Yard, Portsmouth, Virginia, 29 August 1861. (Box-folder 1:77)
      "...father has lost everything...am perfectly disgusted with yankees and negroes...." Endorsement: "...in spite of her feelings Aunt has married 'a yankee'...who came wounded to desolated Hampton...." J[ane] H. M[arr].
    - "Papa" James [James Barron Hope], Atlantic Hotel Reading Room, to his mother and his wife, 1 September 1861. (Box-folder 1:78)
      "The news from Hatteras is very sad"; "the capture of Uncle Sam [Comm. Samuel Barron]."
    - James [Barron Hope] to his mother, 7 September 1861. (Box-folder 1:79)
      "...alleviate your anxiety about Uncle Sam [Comm. Samuel Barron]"; defense of his action at Hatteras.
    - "A Letter to Ex-President Tyler, Flag Officer Forrest and George Booker, of 'Sherwood,' In Vindication of Flag Officer Samuel Barron, C. S. N.," by Capt. [James Barron] Hope,28 September 1861., 11 pages. Adr. (Box-folder 1:80)
      Endorsements and corrections added.
    - "Papa" James to his wife, 8 October 1861. (Box-folder 1:81)
      Letter discusses his return to his post after a visit to his family.
    - H. B. Cary, Yorktown, to His Excellency, President John Tyler, Confederate Congress, Richmond, Virginia, 23 December 1861. (Box-folder 1:82)
      Upon the death of Morrison of the faculty of William and Mary, a recommendation that the place be filled by James Barron Hope, "one of the rising literary men of the state."
    - "Papa" James [Barron Hope], Richmond, to his wife Annie, 11 January 1862. (Box-folder 1:83)
      Letter concerns the crowded condition of Richmond where he had been transferred; "no doubt that a great battle is impending."
    - "Papa" James [Barron Hope], Richmond, to his wife Annie, 18 January 1862. (Box-folder 1:84)
      "I saw Uncle S[amuel Barron]" who has agreed to be his security [for Quartermaster post]; "the news...is in general, cheering."
    - "Papa" James [Barron Hope] to his wife Annie, 22 January 1862. (Box-folder 1:85)
      Letter concerns his new position in the Quartermaster office.
    - [James Barron Hope] to Annie, 8 May 1862., 8 pages. ads. (Box-folder 1:86)
      Letter concerns planned abandonment of Norfolk because "to compete with the North in producing an ironclad Navy is out of the question"; Yorktown will be abandoned but "we grow stronger as we go from the coast." Description of Randolph, Secy of Army, "tall sinewy" and of Mallory, Secy of Navy, "a stupid little man."
    - "Papa" James [Barron Hope], Commandant's Office, Dockyard, Gosport, to his wife Annie, 8 May 1862. (Box-folder 1:87)
      "Our troops are moving off so fast that there shall soon be none left there... the worst that can happen is to be taken prisoner...."
    - R. Forrest, Chief of Bureau, C. S. Navy Department, Richmond, to J[ames] Barron Hope, Richmond, 24 May 1862. (Box-folder 1:88)
      Appointment to the position of Recorder for a Naval Court of Inquiry.
    - [James Barron Hope], Richmond, to Annie, 31 May 1862. (Box-folder 1:89)